Laurențiu Nichitean

https://www.laurnichitean.com

I am a Senior React Developer with more than 10 years of experience in software development, specialized in front-end technologies – React.js, JavaScript, TypeScript. In the last 2+ years I have also worked as a back-end developer using Java with Adobe Experience Manager and Go.





Skills

- React.js
- JavaScript
- Webpack
- Gi
- Yarn
- Typescript

- HTML5
- WebSockets
- Email templates
- AWS
- Kubernetes
- Gulp

- CSS3
- Adobe Experience Manager
- Unix/Linux, Docker
- JSX
- ES6+
- Photoshop

Experience

Senior IT Consultant

10 / 2019 - present

Senior Full-Stack Developer with React.js / Java / AEM

I work as a consultant/contractor/freelancer and help businesses develop their enterprise solutions.

My programming language of choice is JavaScript (front-end solutions using mainly React.js) but I have also used Java for back-end development for Adobe Experience Manager and Go for microservices development. I am constantly looking for new challenges and opportunities to expand my expertise.

IBM

04 / 2019 - 10 / 2019

Full-Stack Lead Developer with DevOps

Developed, tested and deployed new features as part of the BMW Personal Portal project. Participated in code and design reviews, leveraged modern tools and techniques to develop clean, efficient and reusable code. Coached new team members on the project.

IBM

11 / 2017 - 04 / 2019

Senior Front-End Developer

BMW Configurator. Improved integration with Adobe Experience Manager, also provided several recommendations to the application integration environment to improve user experience, expecially on mobile devices.

Pentalog 07 / 2013 - 11 / 2017

Senior Front-End Developer

Development of the second version for a product that provides a service design platform, being the first choice digital toolbox for service designers. Umagus allows you to manage your team, projects, create storyboards, visualize key metrics, then export all results to different file formats.

Freelance Web Developer & Graphic Designer

10 / 2006 - 11 / 2017

Freelance Web Developer & Graphic Designer

WordPress development • PSD to HTML • Crafted web applications using HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery and other JS libraries and frameworks • Designed websites and user interfaces in Adobe Photoshop • Logo and UI Design Custom back-end development using PHP and MySQL • Email development

Education Link Academy 2011 - 2012

Certified Web Designer, Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information Resources Design

Universitatea "Ovidius", Constanța 2006 - 2009

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Information Technology

Interests Latest Web Technologies

Software Architecture Graphic design

User Experience

Certifications | Adobe Certified Expert in Photoshop CS4 01 / 2012

Adobe · License: ADB282481

Languages • English • French • Romanian • German